<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="4.1.0">Jekyll</generator>
<link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
<link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
<updated>2020-06-07T09:55:03-07:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:4000/</id>
<entry>
<title>Day Six</title>
<link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/06/03/sixth.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Day Six" />
<published>2020-06-03T00:00:00-07:00</published>
<updated>2020-06-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:4000/2020/06/03/sixth</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/06/03/sixth.html">&lt;p&gt;6:00 am&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As soon as Barthen’s opens at 6am I head up there to get an extra canteen for Roach and 7 days of oats. The canteen is 2L and costs 1s. It costs me 4S 1C. I have a nice breakfast of porridge, fruit, and bacon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 6:30 Walker comes down, eats a berry and sits with me. She gets a cup of tea while I finish eating. Buba settles down on my shoulder munching something. He makes a joke and I respond in my head. No outward signs of my conversation with Buba.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walker asks me what I fight with. I reply, “my quarterstaff and darts”. She asks about my dagger, I had forgotten about it. She says she fights with the swords when needed, otherwise she can’t show me inside. She also has a dagger that appears and disappears in her gauntlet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She calls Pip to fetch her horse. I ask for Roach too. He tips a fake hat. I stand up and Walker puts a couple of silver on the table and gives the wife a silver for pip. She goes outside and the horses are there. I follow her out. She has a 6”x4” half circle cut out of the saddled infront of where her knee would be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pip is there holding the reins. I give him 2C. Something grabs me by the back and lifts me into the saddle. It was Buba. I compliment him on his strength. We head to the Triboar Trail and head East. Buba tells me he can hear her heartbeat so she’s not dead/undead. If I wanted him to detect magic she would know if she was actively detecting magic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We travel uneventfully until noon. Buba spots a creek ahead that we can water the horses at. It’s been about 30 miles. We unsaddle our horses, she brushes hers and I take Roach down to the river and brush her while she’s drinking. Then I give her an apple and her oats. Walker says that her horse wouldn’t really want that right now, but asks if I have some venison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I start the fire while she pulls out a small tent and sets up her bedroll in it. She gives me a goodberry and says she doesn’t want a potato. She brews some tea then pulls out her book and a camp chair. She gives me one too. I meditate on nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After about 2 hours of reading, at about 7:30, she snaps her fingers and a little ball of light appears, it’s blue. It hovers above the fire. She sits cross legged on the ground and meditates. I visit Roach and walk down to the water. After 2 hours, at 9:30, she gets up. She pats her horse and whispers to him then says she’s going to bed. She says keeping watch isn’t necessary, the blue light is a ward that extends around the camp. Buba says he’s seen the pointy hats do them. He goes out and says it’s totally good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before crawling into her tent, Walker pulls out two bone handles with pieces of metal at the end. She looks at her gauntlet and uses the bone handle on it in a couple of spots then goes to bed. I crawl into my bedroll by the fire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I usually wake up with the sun, but I want to wake up about 6 because I think I need to be with her. I wake up before the sun, but Walker is already up and has started the fire and saddled the horses. There’s eggs cooking on the fire. She says we can go after I eat. I ask if she’s eaten, she has and I gobble up the eggs. She conjures a dragon fruit and I offer it up to Buba. He’s a little suspicious, but he smells it and it smells fresh so he eats it. He wants more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We head out at sunrise, about 7. It’s about 10, Buba tells me there’s a stream to the right nearby. I let Walker know and we head to the river on foot. As we walk towards the water Walker starts smelling the air so I tongue smell it. It doesn’t smell good. We look at each other and say, “ghouls”. Thinking out loud she says, “ghouls are nocturnal” and says we probably have a choice of whether we want to fight them or not. I vote to fight them because they are an undead creature and that is counter to the balance of nature. I know that Ghouls aren’t “tough”, but tough enough. They have multiple attacks per round. They cannot be poisoned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We head down a path, there are three openings in the side of the hill beside us. In front of us there is a cave entrance. From the opening we can see a number of creatures in there and the smell confirms it is ghouls. There might be 5 or 6 that we can see, but there could be more in the background. She says they appear to be sleeping, what do you want to do. I want to investigate the holes on the side first. I do so in order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s very dark and when I attempt to see in the first cave I trigger initiative. A giant spider sprays web at me, but I dodge out of the way and I hear a very loud roar. I cast wind wall across the entrance to the cave to keep the ghouls off our back while we deal with the spiders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walker steps around me and shoots the attacking spider with her bow that materialized from her gauntlet. It liquifies the original spider and the one next to it. I hear a very loud sound from the cave, but I’ve never heard it before. One of the ghouls attempts to go through the wall. He takes half damage. He closes on Walker, but he misses her with both his attacks. I throw a dart at the last spider. He sprays me with webbing, but I can break out of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A non-corporeal creature comes running out of the cave. He roars and I’m frightened. I run away. In four rounds Buba will dispel magic on me and I can come back. From a distance I hear a thunderclap. When I free to do so I sprint back. Walker dealt with everything on her own. There is a pile of ash beside her and she pulls something out of it and puts in her pocket. She asks me if I’m okay and tells me it’s alright when I apologize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So, did these guys have anything good on them?” She said that ghouls don’t often have much on them, but they might have something from other adventurers. Nassira knows that the ghouls wouldn’t likely be holding anything on them. I venture deeper into the cave. There are some rotting boxes in the back of the cave. In box number one there is 24G of ancient or foreign currency I’ve never seen, everything else is dust. In box number two there are 6P, 18G and nothing else. The next box has 24P, a dark green glass bottle with a liquid in it, the last box contains 18P. I tell her what I found. She asks to see one of the coins. She says they’re really old, from the Barzan Empire fell about 3500 years ago. She thinks I may get more for them than they’re worth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She has a gash on her arm, but doesn’t take my offered healing. It’s early afternoon when we resume our journey. We’re following a path that winds around the foothills. I suggest we stop for the night and get an early start. We stop to make camp when we’re about two hours away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we sit she asks me about myself. I get her talking about the encounter. She explains what a Whyte is, she says it’s an extraplanar creature that was likely conjured to project something that has likely long rotted away. “Wow, how boring would that be?”. She pulls out her book to read and our camp chairs. She reads for about 75 minutes then meditates again. I gaze at the stars and get lots in their beauty. She meditates for 50 minutes. She conjures a piece of dragon fruit for Buba again. I take it and instantly it’s gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She asks me if I like music. I mention that I haven’t played my flute in awhile. It’s terrible and I put my flute away and crawl into bed. Walker pulls out a lute thing that does not have a curled neck. It’s amazing. She plays and sings an elven song. The version of elvish sounds weird to me. She seems to have a 5-6 octave range. She wishes me goodnight, offers me a tent, and goes to bed. It takes me about an hour to fall asleep. I had a rough day and I’m unhappy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About two hours after I fall asleep I’m woken by a loud sound with a hand over my mouth. It’s Walker. She shushes me. I see a shape go over me, but I can’t make it out. I ask Buba if it’s the dragon again. He says this one is bigger and it’s red. The first one was young and green. Buba doesn’t know what’s going on. She apologizes for touching me, but says that sometimes dragons of that age can see through them. I say it’s no problem I was just glad she spotted it. She offered to teach me the ward spell if I liked. I demure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She asks if she can give me something. I ask her what she means. She puts a small pin on my cloak. It will alert me if anything approaches the ward or anything super strong, evil, or planar comes within 3 miles max will trigger it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wake up at 5:20. I stow my bedroll near my saddle, start the fire and look for some eggs. I find a nest with 3 large bluebird eggs in it. I make eggs, pan fries with onions, and salt and pepper. Buba brings a rabbit. I roast the rabbit. Walker gets up, looks the same as she did the night before. I offer her breakfast, she thinks about it and then accepts. She pulls out plates and cutlery. She gives the horses a good berry. I serve up breakfast for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She conjures a dragon fruit for Buba. I say I need to learn that one, not the ward. She says it’s super easy, you just need to know where the tree is and reach through. I realize it’s not as easy as she seems to think. We finish and she cleans the plates. I take the rabbit skin.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
<summary>6:00 am</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Day Five</title>
<link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/06/01/fifth.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Day Five" />
<published>2020-06-01T00:00:00-07:00</published>
<updated>2020-06-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:4000/2020/06/01/fifth</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/06/01/fifth.html">
</content>
<summary></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Day Four</title>
<link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/05/19/fourth.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Day Four" />
<published>2020-05-19T00:00:00-07:00</published>
<updated>2020-05-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:4000/2020/05/19/fourth</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/05/19/fourth.html">&lt;p&gt;We are outside the Townmaster’s Hall, Mykiel is revived and has full hit points again. Larno, the wizard, is a short human with a dark beard. He usually wears robes and thinks very highly of himself. He hasn’t been seen for the last two months. He was seen exploring around Tresandar Manor. Raynee, Marielle, and Gemma set out for Alderleaf Farm. We’re going to ask if they know or have seen anything? The other three go to the Lionshield Coster. Mykiel buys arrowheads and declines to buy a rapier at this time. Yenna buys a quarterstaff. This store does not sell magical items. Erak decides to go to Barthen’s Provisions to buy a component pouch. They cost 25g.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We approach the farm. Carp is playing outside. He waves enthusiastically and tells us his mum is inside. We knock on the door and she invites us in. We go in and Carp follows us. We all have tea. I ask about them. Carp says he sees a secret place in the woods that there’s a tunnel. Raynee asks him to draw us a map when he offers to show us. There’s a really tall tree that’s broken in half. Gemma brings up Gundren and asks if she knows any dwarves, Nundro and Tharden. Qelline says she doesn’t know them personally but tells us to talk to Reidoth. She tells us that he set out for ruins just west of Neverwinter Wood there’s a village named Thunertree. Gemma then asks about Larno. She says that she heard of a wizard from the Lord’s Alliance that arrived right around when around the Red Brands showed up. Marielle clarifies that it wasn’t too long before them. We offer help if she needs it, but she declines. Raynee puts 10s on the table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all meet up at Stonehill Inn and head to the Shrine of Luck before going to Tresendar Manor. We see a scholarly, young (in her 100s) acolyte there. She greets us and asks what we’re doing in town. Yenna says we’re looking for our friend, but all we find are more questions and no answers. She says that if we’re here to help we may be able to help her. She is part of the Harpers. She’s recently been asked to ask a banshee, Agatha, about a spellbook. She sought her out, but she didn’t appear. She seems to be genuinely asking for help. I ask if there’s something special about the spellbook. Agatha will answer a question if asked if she appears to us. We need to ask what she knows about the spellbook that belonged to Bowgentle, a legendary mage. The banshee is near a town called Conbarry, it’s gone now, but the Tribor Trail runs right through it. It’s a day or two past the turnoff to Phandalin. Gemma asks why she’s looking for the spellbook. She was asked by her superiors to ask the banshee for the location of the spellbook. Mykiel asks about a reward. She offers us 3 potions of healing and a gift to bring to Agatha. Mykiel asks if this can wait a couple of days. She says the gift may help to get her to appear. I take the jewelled silver comb. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The blessing gives us inspiration&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We loop around Alderleaf Farm and into the woods to go to the secret tunnel entrance. There’s a tunnel going into the side of the hill that the Manor is on. The Manor is large, almost a small castle. The entrance does not appear to be guarded. We do not see anyone. We creep cautiously forward, but we are not as quiet as we think we are. We need to go single file. I go first, Gemma, Raynee, Yenna, Erak is second to last, Mykiel is last.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We come out into a large natural cavern with two bridges over a chasm one to the north and one to the south. There are a few natural stone pillars. We investigate. There are a few sets of footprints that move in various directions. They seem to go in all of the ways available. Lots E-W across S bridge. Most appear to be human, maybe some goblinoid. As we step into the room we hear laughter that seems to come from within our heads, “Who are you?”. Gemma uses her divine sense to locate the laughter. It seems to be north. Erak and Yenna see something behind a pillar. Raynee and I are hanging back, Mykiel is in the trench. It’s a weird one-eyed monster. It asks us what we want here. Raynee and I say we’re looking for our friend. We clarify that it’s Larno. He said he’s a Red Brand, wearing a red cloak. The monster says the wizard’s name is Glassstaff. Yenna asks if the wizard is the monster’s friend. The monster says the wizard lets him feed. Mykiel finds a battered wooden chest under the N bridge. He cautiously opens it with the tip of his sword. 160s, 120g, and 5 malachite gems (15g each), 2 potions of healing, a scroll of augury, and a long sword in a silver chaste scabbard. Erak asks what his name is. He replies that he does not have a name. It looks at Erak, “You didn’t do too well in the army”. We ask which way to go to find Glassstaff. He asks what we’re offering. Yenna asks what he likes. He says corpses. There are human bones in the trench and there is a half-eaten human corpse in there. Yenna points out that he’s obviously not that hungry if he has a half-eaten snack. Mykiel asks the creature if it wants the wizard gone from its area. Yenna asks if he likes it down here. Mykiel asks who else is here. He said he was getting bored. The fight starts. Gemma kills it with a mighty blow and divine smite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mykiel offers a long sword to Gemma, gives the scroll to me, Erak gets the other healing spell, and divides the silver and gold between us. The sword is a +1 long sword that was owned by Aldith Tresendar, The Black Hawk. Mykiel finds two secret doors in the storeroom to the N. The first one is not locked and opens quietly. There’s a tunnel and then the back of another secret door. Larno is behind the door reading a book. We catch him by surprise and attack. We want to weaken him, but keep him alive to get information. He surrenders when Yenna hits him on the head. Raynee webs him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yenna grabs the book he was reading. It appears to be a generic magic book. There is a letter that is addressed to Larno.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Lord Albrek,&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;My spies in Neverwinter tell me that strangers are due to arrive in Phandalin. They could be working for the dwarves. Capture them if you can, kill them if you must, but don’t allow them to upset our plans. See that any dwarven maps in their possession are delivered to me with haste. I’m counting on you, Iarno. Don’t disappoint me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We find 180 sp, 130g, and a silk pouch containing five carnelians (10g each), two peridots (15g each), and one pearl (100g), a scroll of charm person and a scroll of fireball.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Raynee gets the glassstaff.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
<summary>We are outside the Townmaster’s Hall, Mykiel is revived and has full hit points again. Larno, the wizard, is a short human with a dark beard. He usually wears robes and thinks very highly of himself. He hasn’t been seen for the last two months. He was seen exploring around Tresandar Manor. Raynee, Marielle, and Gemma set out for Alderleaf Farm. We’re going to ask if they know or have seen anything? The other three go to the Lionshield Coster. Mykiel buys arrowheads and declines to buy a rapier at this time. Yenna buys a quarterstaff. This store does not sell magical items. Erak decides to go to Barthen’s Provisions to buy a component pouch. They cost 25g.</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Day Five</title>
<link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/05/16/fifth.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Day Five" />
<published>2020-05-16T00:00:00-07:00</published>
<updated>2020-05-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:4000/2020/05/16/fifth</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/05/16/fifth.html">&lt;p&gt;After lunch I decide to wander around the town. I check out the Shrine of Luck. 20’x30’, two stories. Out front is a well. There is a young pretty elven woman pulling water. There is a symbol carved into the stone of the well and then carved over the door again. The Elf is also wearing that symbol around her neck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She greets me openly and warmly. Sister Garaele introduces herself. She’s about my size. She asks me why I’m in Phandalin. I say I was delivering goods and it sounds like the town needs help and now I’m staying. She invites me in for a glass of wine. I go in. There’s a nice sitting room with a decanter of wine and fruit. She asks me what my deal is and I explain. She has a pin on her robe that is a little golden harp. The symbol of The Harpers (An organization that tries to see good happen in the world).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goddess Timora, elven god of good fortune, travellers, and gamblers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She says it’s fortuitous that I’ve arrived because she just received word from her order. They’ve asked her to locate a spellbook with spells unique to our order. There was a temple in Newhaven and during the cataclysm 100s of years ago and it was lost. Recently a group of adventurers has found the ruins. One of them was from their order and the book was gone. They’ve heard rumours that the book is near here. It’s in an area near Coney Berry, roughly 12 leagues away, 2 days on a fast horse. She says she would identify my blade for information regarding the book. I ask about danger, but she doesn’t know. I agree to have my blade read. I place it on the table and she starts chanting. She tells me it’s not cursed. Upon casting another spell she tells me there’s 3 types of magic in this dagger. It’s name is in the old language. Dagger of the Displacer/Displacement, Likely the skin is of a Discplacer beast. She casts again, the dagger has some trigger words: avoidance (Something that would not normally give you a saving throw, I get one. If I make it I get half damage, 3 times in 24hrs. It lasts for one minute and must be said before the initial attack that does not have the saving throw) and displacement (once a day it can project an illusion of the holder that makes it appear that they are 6’ away from where the holder is in a random direction. It will look exactly like me, no sound, touch, or smell, it does move as I move. Lasts up to one minute. My AC is improved by 2 while in force.). There’s no time limit on this mission. I say I will leave in a few days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5-6 months ago, a group of ruffians moved into the area. They have been known to extort the guilds and businesses. They’ve left her alone because she’s religious. A local farmer that refused to pay the money has washed up in the river, his wife and daughter are missing. She is sure that a group of merchants, particularly Halia, would pay handsomely. She believes Halia’s heart is in the right place, but she’s misguided. They hang out at the Sleeping Giant. I ask about Harben and she says that everyone has asked him to do something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She offers me a blessing in the name of Timora and heals me. She asks me to come back and let her know before she leaves. She sticks out her hand then ducks in for a big hug then sends me on my way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;……..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I head towards the smithy. As I go towards it, I hear half the blacksmith’s half of an argument. I see a woman dressed in all black armor with some deep red pops of colour. The gauntlet on her right hand is metal, leather glove on the left. Two hilts coming over her shoulder and two hilts on her left hip. She’s about 5’7” with a slight build, likely not human. She stands with balance and poise and like she could draw and kill without a hesitation. Her hair and face are covered. She has a weird accent. She is mad at the smithy as it’s not what they agreed to. He made her something from diagrams. She has something in her hand and says that metal was not used. His forge wasn’t hot enough to melt the metal for arrow heads. She says they are useless and he says they are the best he’s made or seen. She asks about the metal. He indicates the bench and says he can’t melt it, but he’s willing to work day and night for what she’s paying him. I hear some mumbling and my skin prickles and hair stands on the back of my neck. The forge will be hot enough for the next two hours to melt that metal. Do not disappoint me… He called her Walker. I will find you. She is in the tavern I’m staying at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He calls out to his assistant to bring him his leather gear. I follow her into the tavern. Walker is walking to the wife. She’s very deferential and says the best room is ready. Walker says she just needs a quiet place. She hands a platinum piece over. The wife leaves without taking it and says she couldn’t take that. Walker leaves it on the counter. I head up to the counter where the wife is. I ask who the woman is. She is visibly shaken by my question. She comes by occasionally and keeps to herself. She’s a ranger of the North. Phandalin had 6 rampaging ogres 5 or 6 years ago that were destroying the town. She saved us, stayed one night to rest and then she left. She has a black mare charger. She has been nothing but helpful and doesn’t ask for any money. I ask if there’s room for one more horse in the stable. She calls Pip to get Roach. She gushes about Roach and the guy that had her. The guy said one word and gestured to turn out the light. He had two swords. I point out that Ms. Walker has two. She says one shone bright like the sun and one pulled all the joy from the world, shiny black with mist around it. She warns that there might be spidery lines on the floor in front of Walker’s door and that if you step on them they will hurt. I give her 5 copper to give Pip when she deems appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wander out again. The first thing I see is the costers. I walk in and see a woman behind the counter, Linene. She is a sharp-tongued human woman about 35. She asks me why I’m there. I explain about the work. I say I’ve been using my quarterstaff for a long time and I’d like to see about some new gear. She locks the door due to the Red Brands. She pulls out an ironwood quarterstaff. It’s textured and a wee bit narrower than mine. The bottom 8-9” is covered in some kind of textured skin. I say this should help me defeat the Red Brands. She tells me to go to the Sleeping Giant to get more information. She also tells me about Ms. Walker’s defeat of the ogres too. Linene hasn’t ever seen armor like that. Has not aged since Linene was a little girl. She tells me that when ogres are exposed to sun, they turn to stone. They used them for mortar. The last big mine shut down about 200 years ago. She tells me of a rumour that the Rockseeker brothers have found a mine. She offers me the quarterstaff for 35 gold. I say that sounds more than fair. She then tries to offer me other things. There are some low quality ones, some mulibdimum for 1.5s each and then there are some that are 1g each because they are an alloy, a mixture of steel and silver, and they work against things that can only be hit by silver weapons. She comments on my platinum. Walker’s has a sunburst on one side and a seraphim on the other. I know of no culture that mints this symbol. She offers me potions. I decide they aren’t worth the price. I comment on her system under the floorboard and she says the woodworker made it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been almost exactly two hours so I wander towards Barthen’s to loiter and watch Walker head to get her arrowheads. He was able to make 12. They are luminescent. She is extremely happy and hands him a sack. He says it’s too much, but she ignores him and leaves with her arrowheads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I buy veggies at Barthens then leave. Walker confronts me about watching her. I tell her I was concerned about her intentions. She tells me to just ask her. Then asks about my intentions. I say I want to help them. She says she’s back because she senses they need help again. She advises I can accompany her to deal with the orcs. She says Harben will pay me. I say he’s no longer in charge. She tells me to talk to Celdar. She has blue eyes like the sky with no flecks in her eyes and the whites are perfectly white. She can also speak Yuanti fluently. Up close I can tell she’s not an elf, but does not smell like a human either. I’ve never smelled anything like her. She is “inhumanly” beautiful. She has two dirks on her hip. Her swords look like they should be too big for her.I suspect that her right hand may be the metal gauntlet. She says she will be leaving the inn at 7 to deal with the orc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She heads back to the inn as do I. I put my stuff down in my room. I walk carefully around the cobweb designs on her door and floor. After putting my stuff down I take my dagger out to the town green to attune to my dagger. It takes two hours, but then we are one. At the end I hear the magic words in my head. Apparently it pushed against my magical link with Bubba. He demands the dagger and I hand it over. He sits in my lap and plays with the dagger. He attunes to it. He says I should talk to him about things, especially with anger issues. It isn’t angry now that he’s attuned to it. It hurt him psionically. I offer him fruit, but he’s eaten a TON of apples. I head back to the inn to show him the shinies. He stops me and asks if it feels cold. I downloaded all the info I have about her. He says she walks the worlds. He says the town really needs help and lists all the things I know about and something about a well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I get into the inn and she says dinner is only on for about thirty more minutes. Sundown is about 45 minutes though. I ask about the cobwebs, there’s three overlapping ruins, water, fire, and a trip line. The trip line is a warning. Then there’s a lightning ward underneath that is not a warning. Below that is a cold ward. He says he would only expect pointy hats to have those. He was surprised that she knew them. I show him the ring and the torc. He doesn’t want precious metals, just gems. He smells something on my dagger. I try to smell it too. It smells weird. I’ve never smelled this smell before. He says it smells like underdark and he hasn’t smelled that for 50 years. I tell him the name and he puts it together that it’s a displacer beast. When I told him where I got it he advised me that most magic weapons will resize themselves to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We head down to eat. Walker has the corner table so I take the one against the wall. Holly is there almost immediately. I ask for half a glass of mead. She tells me that there’s roast mutton tonight. I get her to save two plates for Celdar and I. When he comes in he sees Walker and immediately goes over to her and asks why she’s there. He tells her they don’t need her kind of help. She insists then dismisses him. He’s rattled when he comes back. He eats, we chat. He says he’s getting a lot of requests; the Red Brands, the book, and the orcs. He says the Red Brands are priority #1. He tells me to go with her if we’ve teamed up otherwise he’s happy to work with me. When I tell him we’re going after the orcs in the morning he reminds me about the 100g reward. He tells me on Roach it’s about 2 days. The last 5 leagues are in the foothills. Could be 3 days just to get there. He encourages me to do it because it needs to be done. Her horse’s eyes glow at night. He tells me that he found a book in the town hall that spoke about a cataclysm that happened 400 years ago here and the picture of the savior looks like her. Elves only live 600-700 years so even an elf would be showing its age. He advises me that his ring is on fire. His signet ring that has the head of the lion on a sun on it, it’s the symbol of the Lord’s of Light. It tells him when powerful magics are around. He warns me to be careful. I tell him about the cleric and my dagger. He’s going to go in the morning. I examine his sword hilt, it’s onyx and it’s serpent with two jeweled eyes. He says he feels almost dizzy when he looks in its eyes. I tell him about Sseth and that the hilt is his image. If he can’t use it we will work something out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ask him where to get oats for the trip. He tells me to go to Barthen’s and that they open at 6. He also suggests I get an extra canteen. We finish dinner and both head upstairs. He walks briskly in a military fashion with his hand on the palm of the sword. I wish the wife goodnight and compliment her on the dinner. She says he cooks the fancy meals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I head up and Bubba tells me to step into the room and keep the door open. He says he could do something similar. He seems disappointed when I say I don’t need them so I say it couldn’t hurt. I can almost see him because our bond is getting so close now. He says he can do the top one, maybe the middle, and definitely not the bottom one. He just does the top one, it has vocalization and components. I feel a wall of wind hit me and there’s a force at the door. He’s on the wrong side of the door. I stifle laughter as he flies around to the window. He protects that too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He curls up on the pillow taking up a good 2/3rds of it and he’s out like a light. I tuck the gold torc in and under him then go to sleep. I wake up about 4:30am&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
<summary>After lunch I decide to wander around the town. I check out the Shrine of Luck. 20’x30’, two stories. Out front is a well. There is a young pretty elven woman pulling water. There is a symbol carved into the stone of the well and then carved over the door again. The Elf is also wearing that symbol around her neck.</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Day Four</title>
<link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/05/14/fourth.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Day Four" />
<published>2020-05-14T00:00:00-07:00</published>
<updated>2020-05-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:4000/2020/05/14/fourth</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/05/14/fourth.html">&lt;p&gt;Sounds like the goblins may have taken Gundren to Craigmore Castle. We make plans to get the supplies to the cart and back to town. There are 5 chests to bring back to the wagon. We decide to load up the cart in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I go hunting in wolf form but don’t manage to catch anything. Bubba catches three rabbits and Nassira kills them and goes back to the camp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bubba hears an evil voice on the wind so he’s going to check it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He has alcohol in his bag that he is very pleased about. He cleans and dresses the rabbits. Nassira deals with the fire. Then they chat about adventuring and the issues in Phandalin. Cildar, Lord’s of Light have a controlling interest in the town. It used to be a Duchy of the Lords of Light until it shrunk. Rockseeker brothers found the Lost Cave of Echos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They sent a mage to town a while back to get things in order, Larno Albrek. He was sent about 6 months ago to get things ready for the Lords of Light to come in. I tell him about the Red Bandits. Cildar doesn’t seem too fond of the town master, Harben. He also doesn’t seem to think much of elves. ????&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He takes first watch and wakes me at 2:30am. When I wake up he’s making breakfast of rabbit, eggs, and tubers. He admires my saddle. Breakfast was very good. He hides a salt and pepper shaker in his boot. He carries 2 chests for 2 trips. I take one the first time then get Roach and my stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:45am
Everything is in the cart. I hear a “panicked” voice in my head. He tells me to get back to town asap and not to go that way! It’s like him, but not like him. It smells like a huge reptile or a dragon. I reassure him that we’re going back to town right away.
Roach is not built to pull a cart so it’s slow going because I’m not willing to push her hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11am
Roach is looking tired so I call a rest for her. I water her in a stream. I eat some jerky and hand it to him. We munch that while we wait. It takes about half an hour and then she’s ready to go. After lunch, we walk so it’s easier on Roach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stop at 2:30pm for Roach to rest again. I give her water from my canteen. We set off again 50 minutes later. I offer him more jerky, but he declines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6pm
The sun is getting low and there’s a clearing we can camp at. I hear water trickling. He gives me his canteen and a pot to put water in while I water Roach. We eat stew, I don’t really like it much. Bubba comes back and eats the leftovers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I take first watch. Nothing happens. Something happens on his watch though.
While looking for eggs for breakfast he discovered an ogre just over the ridge. He says we can fight it or lead it to town by running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We fight it and win. There is a leather-wrapped rapier. The handle is jet black, the blade is almost radiant. It’s so shiny and bright. I let him take it. He offers me a small bundle. It’s an ornate dagger. It resizes to fit my hand because it’s too big for me. The handle is silver and wrapped in skin. It seems to absorb light. The blade is mat black and appears to absorb light. When I hold it, it shrinks to my size and stays that way. I question if he’s okay giving it to me. He feels it’s a fair trade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He asks if I’m okay with bringing the ogre eye teeth into town for a bounty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I let Bubba know there’s food here if he wants it. There’s no reply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I look around and loot the body. I put the copper, silver, and electrum into a sack and on the cart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cildar makes breakfast and then puts the antlers in the cart. He breaks up camp and waters the horse while I’m examining my dagger. I hear a soft voice in my head that may have been “miss you”. It sounds like my voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:15am
We set out for town. The sun is just cresting the horizon. We both walk beside the cart. He occasionally helps Roach as much as he can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11:15am
We see Phandalin in the distance, about 10 minutes away.
I suggest we go to Barthen’s to drop all this off before we do anything else. We do that.
Elmer gives Celdar two bags of gold. Celdar weights them and gives me one. I got another 25 gold.
Elmer has his kids unload the cart. They each only carry one chest at a time. The cart belongs to Elmer. I ask where the best place to keep Roach is. He offers a night for free for Roach and promises great care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Celdar carries my bag of money for me. He says he has to speak to Harben, the town master. He suggests I convert my money to something lighter at the Miner’s Exchange.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We get to the Exchange. Bubba points out that Halia may give me a better deal because Celdar is here. He lets me enter first. I shoot him a look but enter first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She greets him happily and ignores me. He’s professional and courteous with her. When asked she says it’s going downhill, but he interrupts her to tell her about the “orc horde we defeated nearby” and says that she needs to give me a good deal on my money. I exchange 580 copper, 70 silver, and 455 gold. I keep 12 copper, 5 silver, and 12 gold. She suggests I check in at the weaponsmith for more darts. She offers me 10 50g each, 5 of 100g, or 1 of 500g. She slides me 10 rubies. Celdar examines them and suggests the sapphires instead. I have 5 sapphires. He thanks her and turns to leave. She stops him and tells him about the problems in town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She explains that the Red Brands are terrorizing the town and that Harben is doing nothing about them. She says they hang out at the Sleeping Giant and their headquarters is at Tresendar Manor. She offers us 100g to take out Glassstaff, the leader and bring us any correspondence we find. I think she has ulterior motives for wanting the leader dead. Celdar asks why we shouldn’t just kill them all, not just the leader. She says that they should fall apart if we kill the leader. I think that sounds reasonable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Celdar salutes and leaves. I follow. He says he’s going to see Harben and asks if I would like to come with. I go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harben Wester is a fat, pompous old fool. There’s a small jail in the cellar, two cells. He carries the keys. He greets Celdar like they’re long-lost friends. Celdar is monotone and polite. He asks how things are in “our” town of Phandalin. Harben says things are fine. Celdar asks about the ogre, Harben says they heard about it. Celdar is less than impressed. He asks what happened to the mage they sent to help with problems. Harben says he’s been gone for about 5 months. Celdar pointedly asks why he didn’t tell the Lords of Light. He asks what Harben has done to safeguard “our” mutual investment and interest. He says they have no resources in such a small place. Celdar asks about a town guard or militia given the strong young men here. Harben says it’s a good idea and we’ll get on it. Celdar tells him not to worry about anything, that he’ll do it. He says he needs the office space. He tells him to go home and he’ll send for him if he needs him. Celdar says he will do what needs doing and the city will pay for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harben says there were some travellers on the Triboar trail that reported trouble with a band of orcs near Wyventor. We have 100g for anyone who takes care of it. Celdar says to tell him about the Red Brands. Harben says they’re just a mercenary guild. Celdar threatens him because he knows he’s lying. He tells us about Glassstaff and the Sleeping Giant. Celdar asks why Harben hasn’t done anything about it. He replies that he doesn’t have the manpower. Harben is upset but grabs his coat and leaves. Celdar gets the cell keys from him before he leaves. I wish Celdar luck and we agree to meet for dinner at sunset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I head to the Stonehill Inn for lunch. Toblin, the owner, is there. Trilena wife, son, pip. I walk up to the bar and let him know I need a room and that Celdar will as well. He offers me the marital suite still. I say no so he offers to wait on payment as the people working for the city get free room and board. He says it’s lunchtime and my stomach growls loudly. He says lunch will be brought to my table. He then says they little white mice. I look confused. He apologizes and says lunch is coming. I ask him what it is, it’s mutton stew, bread, and cheese. It is delicious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sit back and relax. When I do Toblin offers his son to carry my bags. I decline so he gives me my key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sit and sip my mead while watching the people of the town.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
<summary>Sounds like the goblins may have taken Gundren to Craigmore Castle. We make plans to get the supplies to the cart and back to town. There are 5 chests to bring back to the wagon. We decide to load up the cart in the morning.</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Day Three</title>
<link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/05/12/third.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Day Three" />
<published>2020-05-12T00:00:00-07:00</published>
<updated>2020-05-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:4000/2020/05/12/third</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/05/12/third.html">&lt;p&gt;We start off with a goblin battle first thing. Everyone has very low hit points and no spell slots left. Everyone that could, healed and then set off after Mykiel and Erak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three ran away that we had left alive. The goblin leader, Yemik, left threatened the life of Gundren’s guard, Cildar. They offered to leave us Cildar if we let them go and we agreed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cildar was unconscious and I healed him. He asked about Gundren. Bugbear had orders to waylay Gundren and Cildar. The Black Spider sent word that the dwarf was to be brought to him and Gundren was taken away. We think Gundren has been taken to Craigma Castle. He told us The Black Spider is after the Gundren brothers. They found the entrance to a long lost cave, Way something Cave. Gundren had a map to this cave. Probs sent map and dwarf to “chief of the clan”, but doesn’t know where.
Mykiel asked if they were coming with supplies, but they just had their own stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suggested we go back to the wagon and head to town with the supplies we were hired to take. We get back to the trail with no issues and find cart and horse with supplies where we left them. We head to Phandalin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cildar mentions that contact there is a wizard named Lamo Albrek. He travelled there about 2 months ago to restore order, but no word has come back. Cildar is a member of the Lord’s Alliance and is going to speak to Iamo and help the Gundren brothers. We make it to Phandalin around nightfall. The Town is much smaller now than the ruins show about the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cildar recommends the Stonehill Inn for the night. We go there. Mykiel requests we stop at the smithy before we leave town. Cildar pays for the night because we saved him. He tells us to come to see him after we’ve all rested. He will be at Townmaster’s Hall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have dinner together at the inn. Just regular townsfolk at the inn. Lean and balding human male, wise-looking female halfling, the innkeeper is a short friendly young human male. Ask if the people are regulars, the man is Elmar, the halfling is Qelline. We invite them over for around. Mykiel invites them over, the halfling demures. He asks her where she’s going. She’s going to Alderlea Farm, she owns it. Her son, Carp, is only 10 and is home alone. He talks to the Elmar next. He comes over. We are supposed to deliver them to Elmar Barthen at Barthen’s Provisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elmar says the town is small and relatively new. The Red Brands have been shaking down the businesses. They are a band of local nonsense, they act like they’re in charge around here. They’ve been here for a while. Elmar says people would be very grateful if they were taken care of. There’s a town master. Gemma asked Nundro and Tharden, Gundren’s brothers. We told him about the Black Spider taking Gundren. He told us to see the town master, Harben Wester. Mykiel asked where the Red Brands live. Elmar said they frequent the Sleeping Giant’s Taphouse, but doesn’t know where the hideout is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yenna and Raynee go over to the Sleeping Giant to check out the Red Brands. They are antagonistic from the porch when Yenna and Raynee walk up towards the inn. Yenna flirts then asks who’s in charge. Raynee casts a minor illusion of her name being called and pulled Yenna away. She waved a flirty goodbye. Raynee reported that trouble happened and Yenna said nothing happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wake up feeling fantastic (level 2). We decide to drop off the provisions at Barthen’s first. We received our pay and he told us to see Gundren about hazard pay. We asked about the leader of the Red Brands, he didn’t know. He told us to talk to the town master. So we go there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harben is a fat and pompous looking old fool. Cildar is in the back of the room and attempting to avoid looking at the town master. Yenna walks around the desk and seats herself on the desk next to his chair. He harumphs. Then asks if we’re here to help with the orcs. “Travellers have reported that orcs are attacking them off to the East near Triboar Trail.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yenna asks about the Red Brands. He says they’re just a mercenary guild and not that much trouble. We think he believes what he’s saying. Mykiel asks him where they come from and where their hangout/house is. Tresendar Manor. It’s at the top of the hill to the East of town. Raynee asks if it’s more dangerous up there than down here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yenna says Gundren asked us to conduct some business with their leader and that we lost it. He does not believe her. He does tell us the leader’s name is Glassstaff. Mykiel asks where the Rockseeker brothers are. He says he doesn’t keep track of everyone in town. Gemma asks where they might hang out. He says Cildar would probably know. Mykiel asks if there is a bounty on the Red Brands. Harben sputters and throws us out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gemma and Marielle go over to talk to Cildar. We thank him and ask him about what happened and if he saw Gundren’s brothers. He says they’ve gone missing. They’ve not been seen recently. They didn’t tell anyone where it was. Gemma asked if Gundren and his brothers were close. They were on good terms. They’ve been gone a few days. He does not know where they were last seen. But that they were South of town. Cildar wants to find the brothers to bring the Wave Echo Cave. He needs assistance to find Iamo. He was last seen near Tresendar manor they live in. Gemma asks how many people know of the cave. He replies that nobody has seen it in years. He does not think the Red Brands have anything to do with the cave. Cildar confirms the orc reports and says he thinks the reward is 100g to any group that takes care of the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
<summary>We start off with a goblin battle first thing. Everyone has very low hit points and no spell slots left. Everyone that could, healed and then set off after Mykiel and Erak.</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Day Three 6:30 am</title>
<link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/05/10/third.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Day Three 6:30 am" />
<published>2020-05-10T00:00:00-07:00</published>
<updated>2020-05-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:4000/2020/05/10/third</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/05/10/third.html">&lt;p&gt;Commune with nature until the sun comes up
It feels balanced to me
Get camp cleaned up, Roach hidden, tack hidden
Ask Roach to stay nearby
Bubba and I set off up the trail
I’m keeping an eye out for traps, but not super closely because there weren’t any last time
I’m asking Bubba what to expect inside
I linger in the edge of the trees until I get answers from Bubba&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clang the Bug Bear with a small stack of javelins beside him&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guy with spider thing on his shoulder
Dark skin, white hair, mean looking, angry that Gundren was hurt so bad&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Symbol of Rising Moon on supplies&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long rest with Celdar then transport stuff down to the wagon&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
<summary>Commune with nature until the sun comes upIt feels balanced to meGet camp cleaned up, Roach hidden, tack hiddenAsk Roach to stay nearbyBubba and I set off up the trailI’m keeping an eye out for traps, but not super closely because there weren’t any last timeI’m asking Bubba what to expect insideI linger in the edge of the trees until I get answers from Bubba</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Day Two</title>
<link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/05/07/second.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Day Two" />
<published>2020-05-07T00:00:00-07:00</published>
<updated>2020-05-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:4000/2020/05/07/second</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/05/07/second.html">&lt;p&gt;Try to give Bubba fruit, he’s not there
Go back to the inn, The waitress (Holly) there, ask about a horse to buy
Harben Wester, town magistrate - he would have
She sent to Phandalin Miner’s Exchange
Woman, Halia Thorton, 30yrs pleasant+ looking, blonde
Four riding horses
Bay, old
Dappled grey, youngest, well built, 3yrsish, bigger, stronger, 15.5 hands, mare, left behind by Lord of Light Scout, never came home, the magistrate ruled that store could sell to recoup
Phandalin Miner’s Exchange - Mission
Come back Halia Thorton will have a mission
Back at Inn
Farmers/miner’s arguing about something and looking at me. They’re trying to hide that
Took hood down. Smiled next time they looked
One came over, stands over the table, gestures to the empty chair. Offered him to sit
Introduced myself and asked wtf looking over.
He has a job that needs doing.
Extorting local businesses for protection
One’s dead, wife and daughter missing
Hideout, the old Manor House, Tresadore Manor, down the road past inn
Talk to Magistrate, (Town Master), Harben Wester
Potential reward
Halia would give money back if taken care of
Hanging out at Sleeping Giant
Buddy wants to buy me a drink, but unfortunate looking.
Tom buys me an ale
Asks me why I’m purple
Explain about purple desert and lake
Says poem in another language
Nan was half-elf
Town used to be more prosperous
Nan had to move on when no more money
Used to be a mining town
They dried up
Pa was a miner, now he farms
Have hops
Brought in from Tribor
Own brewery with hops and barley
Phandalin Tavern
Wheelhouse - good rep abroad
High Mountain Spirits
Gundren owns a mine
Tom had never heard of it though
Works at the Alderfield farm
Room
Table
Desk - oil lamp
Night table - oil lamp
Wall sconce - oil lamp
Nicest room in the house
Queen/double bed
Clean sheets
2’x2’ window overlooking the shrine
Window fully open, fruit on the table for Bubba, let him know it was there
He comes back and wolfs down grapes then curls up on the other pillow and falls asleep.
He has a big gash on his left-wing, caked blood, but seems okay
I know that indigo is the second oldest, about 50yrs
I know he’s super resistant to magic
Day 2: 7:17am
Bubba is still asleep
Go down for breakfast
She brings over eggs, toast, sausages
Ask for Trax
Get 6 sausages in oilcloth
Bubba wakes up when I get in
I heal him
He scouted the cave
Big spiders in there with blindvision
I give him the sausages
He picks a plum and we each eat one
He asks if I’ve had dragon fruit
Never, but it’s now a mission to get it
We head to get Roach, hood up
The stable boy says put oats in the left saddlebag, one night’s worth
Roach
15.5 hands
Arabian
Dappled grey
Looks fast and nimble
SUPER rich saddle
Tooling, metalwork
Two saddlebags
Bracket for two swords on the right-hand side
Bedroll on saddle
Roach is skeptical so I cast animal friendship
Bubba can talk to him and tells me he’s waiting for someone and asks if the horse belongs to me
I tell Bubba to tell Roach that I would be coming back to the town after we’re done
We get to the spot on the road, it’s 6 pm
I set up camp and change into wolf form to hunt
A strige is above me in a tree looking for prey, it hasn’t seen me yet
Bubba recommends a crossbow
There are 4 of them
I kill them with moonbeam
Bubba had caught 3 rabbits
We cooked and ate them&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2-3 minutes after we settle into sleep Bubba tells me to shush and a big shadow crosses the moon. It was a green dragon.
He doesn’t like the coloured ones, says they’re mean spirited and dumb
The gold ones are honest and will stick to a deal, silver ones kinda, green ones are just liars and mean.
We go to sleep&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
<summary>Try to give Bubba fruit, he’s not thereGo back to the inn, The waitress (Holly) there, ask about a horse to buyHarben Wester, town magistrate - he would haveShe sent to Phandalin Miner’s ExchangeWoman, Halia Thorton, 30yrs pleasant+ looking, blondeFour riding horsesBay, oldDappled grey, youngest, well built, 3yrsish, bigger, stronger, 15.5 hands, mare, left behind by Lord of Light Scout, never came home, the magistrate ruled that store could sell to recoupPhandalin Miner’s Exchange - MissionCome back Halia Thorton will have a missionBack at InnFarmers/miner’s arguing about something and looking at me. They’re trying to hide thatTook hood down. Smiled next time they lookedOne came over, stands over the table, gestures to the empty chair. Offered him to sitIntroduced myself and asked wtf looking over.He has a job that needs doing.Extorting local businesses for protectionOne’s dead, wife and daughter missingHideout, the old Manor House, Tresadore Manor, down the road past innTalk to Magistrate, (Town Master), Harben WesterPotential rewardHalia would give money back if taken care ofHanging out at Sleeping GiantBuddy wants to buy me a drink, but unfortunate looking.Tom buys me an aleAsks me why I’m purpleExplain about purple desert and lakeSays poem in another languageNan was half-elfTown used to be more prosperousNan had to move on when no more moneyUsed to be a mining townThey dried upPa was a miner, now he farmsHave hopsBrought in from TriborOwn brewery with hops and barleyPhandalin TavernWheelhouse - good rep abroadHigh Mountain SpiritsGundren owns a mineTom had never heard of it thoughWorks at the Alderfield farmRoomTableDesk - oil lampNight table - oil lampWall sconce - oil lampNicest room in the houseQueen/double bedClean sheets2’x2’ window overlooking the shrineWindow fully open, fruit on the table for Bubba, let him know it was thereHe comes back and wolfs down grapes then curls up on the other pillow and falls asleep.He has a big gash on his left-wing, caked blood, but seems okayI know that indigo is the second oldest, about 50yrsI know he’s super resistant to magicDay 2: 7:17amBubba is still asleepGo down for breakfastShe brings over eggs, toast, sausagesAsk for TraxGet 6 sausages in oilclothBubba wakes up when I get inI heal himHe scouted the caveBig spiders in there with blindvisionI give him the sausagesHe picks a plum and we each eat oneHe asks if I’ve had dragon fruitNever, but it’s now a mission to get itWe head to get Roach, hood upThe stable boy says put oats in the left saddlebag, one night’s worthRoach15.5 handsArabianDappled greyLooks fast and nimbleSUPER rich saddleTooling, metalworkTwo saddlebagsBracket for two swords on the right-hand sideBedroll on saddleRoach is skeptical so I cast animal friendshipBubba can talk to him and tells me he’s waiting for someone and asks if the horse belongs to meI tell Bubba to tell Roach that I would be coming back to the town after we’re doneWe get to the spot on the road, it’s 6 pmI set up camp and change into wolf form to huntA strige is above me in a tree looking for prey, it hasn’t seen me yetBubba recommends a crossbowThere are 4 of themI kill them with moonbeamBubba had caught 3 rabbitsWe cooked and ate them</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Day One</title>
<link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/05/06/first.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Day One" />
<published>2020-05-06T00:00:00-07:00</published>
<updated>2020-05-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:4000/2020/05/06/first</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/05/06/first.html">&lt;p&gt;Gundren and Celdar Hallwinter
$50
Take to Barthen’s Provisions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;short friendly human, Toben (bartender)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elmer, 50-year-old human. Friendly. Owner of the biggest trading post around&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grundren’s brothers
Nundro, Tharden
Late by 3 or 4 days
Found a cave, Echo Cave or something. Down South.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talk to Harben (leader) at Townmaster’s Hall
**Need to deal with the Red Brands
Bandits, robbing people, harassing people, E of town, hideout!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
<summary>Gundren and Celdar Hallwinter$50Take to Barthen’s Provisions</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Day Two</title>
<link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/05/05/second.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Day Two" />
<published>2020-05-05T00:00:00-07:00</published>
<updated>2020-05-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:4000/2020/05/05/second</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/05/05/second.html">&lt;p&gt;Mykiel spotted a goblin behind a thicket of trees and took a shot with his bow. We got a surprise attack on them. We easily defeated the two goblins outside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hear the sounds of someone/something eating down in the cave and we see a bridge. We distract two tied up wolves with 2 fresh rabbits and 2 pieces of jerky. We set off down the path leaving them happily eating. We were not as stealthy as we wanted to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mykiel was in front and spotted two goblins. The ground started to crumble beneath his feet, he saved himself, but that is now impassible. We hear a loud roar past the bridge and a huge wave of water comes down the tunnel. We were all okay, but as Raynee was examining the area that we had been in two goblins approached us. We hit one of them and they retreated back down the tunnel. Erak and I held our actions. Raynee created an illusion of a pseudo wyvern and Yenna made it roar. Raynee reported that there were 5 goblins up ahead in the tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There turned out to be 5 goblins, a wolf, and a bugbear. Erak exploded the bug bear’s head. When the bugbear died the remaining 3 goblins surrendered. Gemma took care of the wolf by chopping its head clean off. Raynee discovered a key on the bugbear. We opened the chest and got 100 copper, and 19 silver each. Raynee took a small emerald frog statue with gold orbs for eyes, and Mykiel and Yenna each took a healing potion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Raynee questioned the goblins. They were afraid and said that the bugbear was in charge. They said Gundren was dead, but his guard was still around and pointed across the bridge. Raynee sent one of the goblins outside with the wolf’s body to bury it nicely and if it warned anyone and it would end badly for them. The first was too weak and so was the second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mykiel set off to investigate and some of us wanted a short rest. Mykiel alerted a goblin to our presence, triggering a battle.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
<summary>Mykiel spotted a goblin behind a thicket of trees and took a shot with his bow. We got a surprise attack on them. We easily defeated the two goblins outside.</summary>
</entry>
</feed>
